Guide to the Louis Ginsberg Papers, 1920-1976
Department of Special Collections
Louis Ginsberg Papers,
1920-1976
Special Collections M0951
Ginsberg, Louis Ginsberg, Allen
0.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
The material in this collection was sold to Stanford as part of M0733, the Allen Ginsberg Papers.
BIOGRAPHY
Louis Ginsberg (1896-1976) was a poet, English teacher, and socialist. His writings appeared in the New York Times and The New York Herald as well as several poetry anthologies, including Modern American and Modern British Poetry (ed. by Louis Untermeyer). Louis Ginsberg and his first wife Naomi had two sons, Eugene Brooks and Irwin Allen Ginsberg. Eugene Brooks became a successful lawyer and a poet in his own right. Ginsberg's youngest son, Allen Ginsberg, became a major literary figure as one of the founders of the Beat Generation. Ginsberg divorced his severely mentally ill first wife, Naomi, in the mid-1940's. In 1949, he married Edith Ginsberg with whom he spent the rest of his life.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This collection contains typed manuscripts and photostats of typed drafts and published works by Louis Ginsberg. Also contains several letters between Louis Ginsberg and his son Allen Ginsberg regarding a joint publishing project.
CONTAINER LIST
- Attic of the past. Boston: Small, Maynard, & Co., ca. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Collected poems project (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The everlasting minute and other poems. New York: Liveright Publishing, ca. 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Magic Fountain: a novel, tms (photocopy). pp. 1-100 n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Magic Fountain: a novel, tms (photocopy). pp. 101-170 n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Magic Fountain: a novel, tms (photocopy). pp. 171-222 n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Morning in Spring. New York: William Morrow & Co., ca. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Nothing else but a rhyme, clipping, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Our times: a book of poems, tms. [1 of 2] ca. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Our times: a book of poems, tms. [2 of 2] ca. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Our times, tms, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Paterson's principal poet, tms. Introduction by Eugene Brooks n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Poems by the Ginsbergs, ams with some tms, n.d. | (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous poems, tms. [1 of 6] n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous poems, tms. [2 of 6] n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous poems, tms. [3 of 6] n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous poems, tms. [4 of 6] n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous poems, tms. [5 of 6] n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous poems, tms. [6 of 6] n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with William Walling, Rutgers University 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Rutgers University 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- O-Pun mind / by Louis Ginsberg. Weekly column 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Reviews 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Clippings 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)